# Joey Chau

I am a web developer with project management experience, and a background in technical engineering design. My passion for building things, puzzle-solving, and all things aesthetic has fueled me in developing responsive and accessible web apps with dry, reusable code.

(416) 417-3109 joeymchau@gmail.com

#### Portfolio:

www.chauJoey.com GitHub

### **RECENT PROJECTS**

## **fresh vibes** — React / Firebase

A music-blogging platform for users to share tracks and albums from bandcamp. Users can like their favourite posts, and create their own posts with banner images provided by the Unpslash API.

## view live here

# Komami Code — jQuery / SCSS

A fully responsive memory game influenced by the Konami Code. Keyboard users can use the WASD keys to mimic directions, and touch screen users can tap the d-pad on the controller on the screen.

#### view live here

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

# Freelance Web Developer

APR 2020 - Present

- Designed and built a responsive multi-page eCommerce website with jQuery and Bootstrap
- Instructed client on using Contentful API GUI to dynamically add and remove products from the website

## view live here

# **Quality and Project Engineer** — ACS Corp.

APR 2018 - APR 2020

- Implemented strict form control on data logs using VBA for better search capabilities, and discourage non-descriptive records
- Established timelines for new product launches, minimizing gap in product supply for contract customers
- Created project proposals for automotive OEM clients in accordance to IATF Standards

#### **EDUCATION**

# Juno College — Web Development Immersive

AUG 2020 - OCT 2020

# University of Toronto — BASc in Mechanical Engineering

SEP 2009 - JUN 2015

#### **SKILLS**

React
JavaScript & jQuery
Git & GitHub
REST APIs / Firebase
HTML5, CSS3, SCSS
WCAG Accessibility
Responsive Design
Analytical Thinking
Time Management